[柯克] 舰长日志，星历5423.4
[Kirk] Captain's Log : Star date 5423.4.
我们正在绕吉迪恩运行，它还不是
We are orbiting the planet Gideon, which is still not a member...
星际联邦成员
of the United Federation of Planets.
条约谈判一直很艰难
The treaty negotiations have been difficult...
吉迪恩一直拒绝
because Gideon has consistently refused...
联邦代表团踏入他们的国土
the presence of a delegation from the Federation on its soil...
或飞船传感器的任何监视
or any surveillance by the ship's sensors.
他们最终同意由一人组成的代表团
They have finally agreed to a delegation of one.
他们坚持要求是企业号的舰长
They insisted it be the captain of the Enterprise.
因此，我要立即传送下去
I am, therefore, beaming down at once.
真可惜吉迪恩不允许集体访问，史波克先生
It's too bad Gideon isn't cleared for general visitation, Mr. Spock.
根据提交给联邦的
According to the physio cultural reports...
自然文化报告，它是天堂
submitted to the Federation, it's a paradise.
我很想听听你的描述，舰长
I shall be interested in hearing your description, Captain.
不会让你久等的
You won't have long to wait.
- 乌乎拉上尉  - 是的，史波克先生
- Lieutenant Uhura. - Yes, Mr. Spock.
我们得到吉迪恩的最终批准了吗？
Do we have final clearance from Gideon?
是的，他们为我们提供了坐标
Yes. They have provided us with the coordinates for beam down.
把坐标给我好吗？
May I have them, please?
- 875  - 875
- 875. - 875.
- 020  - 020
- 020. - 020.
[乌乎拉] 079
[Uhura] 079.
079.
我们走吧，史波克先生
Let's go, Mr. Spock.
传送
Energizing.
史波克先生？
Mr. Spock?
史波克先生，我还没有被传送下去
Mr. Spock. I have not yet transported down.
你为什么在确认传送之前离开你的岗位？
Why did you leave your post before confirming transport?
史波克先生？
Mr. Spock?
史波克？
Spock?
轮机部？斯科特先生？
Engineering. Mr. Scott?
斯科提？
Scotty!
乌乎拉上尉，马上报告
Lieutenant Uhura, report immediately.
所有舰桥人员，立即回答
All bridge personnel, report immediately.
柯克呼叫船员，船上有人吗？
Kirk to crew. Is anyone aboard?
医务室？麦考伊医生？
Sick Bay. Dr. McCoy?
老骨头，老骨头，回答我
Bones? Bones, answer me.
老骨头…
Bones.
我们仍在绕吉迪恩运行
We're still orbiting Gideon.
[柯克] 宇宙，最后的边疆
[Kirk] Space, the final frontier.
这些是星舰企业号的航程
These are the voyages of the star ship Enterprise.
它的五年任务：探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: to explore strange new worlds,
寻找新生命和新文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇踏前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
吉迪恩的伤口
The Mark of Gideon
我一个人在企业号上
I'm alone on the Enterprise.
我已经搜遍了船上的每个区域，都找不到船员的踪迹
I have searched the ship and still cannot find a trace of the crew...
或船员如何消失的迹象
or an indication of how its disappearance was managed.
一件事显而易见，我经历了一次失忆
The one thing that is obvious is that I suffered a memory lapse...
在那段时间里，我的手臂受伤了
during which time I bruised my arm.
这让我有些恼火
It is causing me some irritation.
吉迪恩人正在联系我们，史波克先生
Gideon is contacting us, Mr. Spock.
- 把它放在屏幕上  - 是的，长官
- Put it on the screen. - Aye, sir.
柯克舰长，我是霍丁大使
Captain Kirk. This is Ambassador Hodin.
议会正在等待您的到来
The council is still awaiting your arrival.
我是史波克先生，霍丁大使
This is Mr. Spock, Ambassador Hodin.
柯克舰长几分钟前就被传送下去了
Captain Kirk was transported down minutes ago.
- 那不可能，- 我亲自传送的他
- That's impossible. - I transported him myself.
他从未到过
He never arrived.
他被直接传送到了你的议会厅
He was beamed directly to your council chambers.
请验证您的坐标
Please verify your coordinates.
875.
020.
- 079  - 坐标已确认
- 079. - Coordinates confirmed.
我们给了你准确的坐标
We gave you the exact coordinates,
这应该把柯克舰长带到这个房间里
which should have brought Captain Kirk directly to this very room.
我没有质疑这一点，先生
I am not questioning that, sir.
如果他不在这，史波克先生
If he is not here, that is your own responsibility, Mr. Spock,
那是你自己和你的员工的责任
and that of your staff.
我不否认这一点，我并不是要责怪你们的人员
I do not deny that, sir. I am not attempting to blame your personnel.
很高兴听到它
We are glad to hear that.
我们将把它记入这次不幸事件的记录中
We shall enter it into the records of this most unfortunate event.
阁下，即使有像我们这样
Your Excellency, even with intricate machinery...
微妙平衡的复杂机器
as delicately balanced as ours,
也有处理错误的余地
there is still a margin for error which must be dealt with.
有可能柯克舰长
It is possible that Captain Kirk...
在吉迪恩的另一处物质化
materialized on some other part of Gideon.
希望是在陆地上
Let us hope it was on dry land.
阁下
Your Excellency.
我可以切入正题吗？
May I cut right to the heart of the matter?
请允许我传送下来进行搜索
I request permission to beam down.
拒绝，你们联邦一定知道我们坚守的传统
Permission denied.Your Federation must be aware of our jealous tradition of isolation...
避免一切污染性接触
from all contaminating contacts...
与其他星系行星的暴力性质隔离开来
with a violent nature of planets of other star systems.
阁下，敌对星系之间的战争
Your Excellency, the wars between opposing star systems...
在我们的星系中不再盛行
no longer prevail in our galaxy.
如果您能授予权限…
If you will grant permission
我们将进行彻底的搜索
Of course, we shall institute a thorough search.
与此同时，史波克先生，我建议您检查一下你的机器
In the meantime, I suggest that you look to your machinery.
[舒一口气]
[ Sighs ]
我们必须彻底承认外交的目的
We must acknowledge once and for all that the purpose of diplomacy...
是延长危机
is to prolong a crisis.
那我们还在等什么？我们又不是外交官
Well, what are we waiting for? We're not diplomats!
我们是联邦的代表，医生
We are representatives of the Federation, Doctor.
这并不意味着我们必须表现得像孩子一样，听外交官的愚蠢演讲
That doesn't mean we have to listen to some fool lecture by a diplomat!
不幸的是，外交是我们目前唯一可用的方式
Unfortunately, diplomacy is the only channel available at the moment.
星球屏蔽了我们的传感器，我们无法扫描它
The planet is shielded from our sensors. We cannot scan it.
我们无法选择坐标，必须由吉迪恩人提供
We are unable to select coordinates. They must be provided by Gideon.
我们就不应该同意规定
We should never have agreed to such restrictions.
我们没有，契科夫先生，是联邦
We did not, Mr. Chekov. The Federation did.
- 乌乎拉上尉  - 是的，史波克先生
- Lieutenant Uhura. - Yes, Mr. Spock.
立即联系星际舰队，说明我们的问题
Contact Starfleet immediately. Explain our problem.
请求允许使用我们可以使用的一切手段
Request permission to use every means at our disposal...
来搜寻柯克舰长
to press the search for Captain Kirk.
- 马上，长官  - 有其他可能吗？
- At once, sir. - Are there any other possibilities?
有无数可能，契科夫先生
There are endless, Mr. Chekov.
那我们从哪里开始，史波克先生？
Well, where do we start, Mr. Spock?
使用传感器扫描360度
Institute a sensor scan 360 degrees,
每次1度
one degree at a time.
你是说你要为他扫描空间？
You mean you're gonna scan space for him?
- 但这可能需要数年时间  - 那么越早开始越好
- But, sir, that could take years. - The sooner you begin, the better.
是的，长官
Aye, sir.
[开门]
[Door Opens]
你是谁？
Who are you?
奥多纳，是的，我的名字是奥多纳
Odona! Yes, my name is Odona.
你为什么把我带来这里？
Why did you bring me here?
你在我的船上做什么？
What are you doing on my ship?
这整艘船是你的吗？
Is this entire ship yours?
不是我的私人财产，但我是舰长
Not my personal property, but I'm the captain.
你拥有这一切吗？
Oh, and you have it all to yourself?
目前看来，是我们拥有一切
It seems, at the moment, we have it all to ourselves.
噢！
Oh!
你弄疼我了，舰长
You're hurting me, Captain
柯克，抱歉，詹姆斯·柯克，而且不是我带你来的
Kirk. I'm sorry. James Kirk. And I didn't bring you here.
- 如果不是你带我来的…  - 是的，谁带你来的？
- If you didn't bring me... - That's right. Who brought you here?
我不知道
I don't know.
你…
You
你来之前发生了什么？
What happened before you came here?
试着回忆，这很重要
Try to remember. It's important.
我好像站在一个…
It seems I was standing in a
是的，我站在一个大礼堂里
Yes. I was standing in a large auditorium...
挤满了人
crowded with people.
成千上万人紧贴在我身上，我几乎无法呼吸
Thousands pressed in against me. I could hardly breathe.
我在为氧气而战，尖叫着要出去
I was fighting for oxygen, screaming to get out.
不要害怕
Don't be afraid.
我没有，但你有麻烦了
I'm not, but you are troubled.
我似乎是我的船员中唯一留在企业号上的人
I seem to be the only one of my crew left on board the Enterprise.
430个人
Four hundred and thirty,
显然我是唯一留下的
and l, apparently, am the only one left.
抱歉，我希望我能帮上忙
I'm sorry. I wish I could help.
也许你可以，把剩下的告诉我
Maybe you can. Tell me the rest.
你是在为氧气而战吗？尖叫着离开那里？
You were fighting for oxygen, screaming to get out of there.
然后突然，我就在这里,在你的船上了
And then l... Suddenly I was here on this, on your ship.
还有这么多空间
And there was all this space.
和自由，我只想摇摆
And the freedom! I just wanted to float!
然后你就在那里了
And then, there you were.
你登上企业号多久了？
How long have you been aboard the Enterprise?
我不知道，不久
I don't know. Not long.
- 这重要吗？  - 有可能，跟我来
- Is it important? - It might be. Come with me.
乌乎拉上尉，星际舰队回应我们的请求了吗？
Lieutenant Uhura, has Starfleet honored our request with a reply?
还没有回应，长官
There has been no response as yet, sir.
你有没有告诉他们舰长的生命危在旦夕？
Did you advise them the captain's life is at stake?
是的，长官，他们坚持必须将其提交给联邦
Yes, sir. They insist the matter must be referred to the Federation.
- 什么部门？  - 行星条约局
- What department? - The Bureau of Planetary Treaties.
- 直接联系他们  - 我联系了，史波克先生
- Contact them directly. - I did, Mr. Spock.
他们要求我们必须通过星际舰队的渠道
They insist that we must go through Starfleet channels.
舰长失踪，这就是他们想出的最好的办法？
With the captain lost, that's the best they could come up with?
外交官和官僚的职能可能不同
Diplomats and bureaucrats may function differently,
但达到了完全相同的结果
but they achieve exactly the same results.
我生命中少了九分钟
Nine minutes of my life has been lost.
我不明白
I don't understand.
从我传送到吉迪恩
Between the time I tried to beam down to Gideon...
到发现自己在这儿，时间过了九分钟
and the time I found myself here, nine minutes have disappeared.
- 那段时间发生了什么？  - 什么是吉迪恩？
- What happened during those minutes? - What is Gideon?
那是你的家乡，你来的星球
That's your home, the planet that you come from.
- 是吗？  - 嗯，一定是
- Is it? - Well, it must be.
吉- 吉迪恩？我不知道什么吉迪恩
G- Gideon? I don't know any Gideon.
这不可能
It's impossible.
我们在吉迪恩上空的同步轨道上
We were in synchronous orbit over the capital city of Gideon.
我试着传送下去，出了岔子
I tried to beam down, something happened,
你被从吉迪恩传送上船了
and you were beamed aboard from Gideon!
我不这么认为
I do not think so.
我们不再在吉迪恩上空了
We're no longer over Gideon.
- 我们在哪？  - 我不知道
- Where are we? - I don't know.
我不熟悉那个象限
I'm not familiar with that quadrant.
奥多纳
Odona,
你必须意识到我们不是偶然来到这里的
you must realize that we're not here by accident.
某种力量，某种智慧
Some force, some intelligence...
为了某种目的…安排了这一切
has arranged this for a purpose.
舰长，之前我说我不害怕
Captain, before I said I wasn't afraid.
现在我怕了
Now I am.
大使要说话，他们要求可视通信
The ambassador will speak. They're requesting visual communication.
好消息！非常好的消息，史波克先生
Good news! Very good news indeed, Mr. Spock.
你的舰长绝对不在吉迪恩，根据你的要求
Your captain is definitely not on Gideon. As you requested,
我们进行了最彻底的搜索
we made a most thorough search, and you will be relieved to know...
你可以放心调查其他可能性
that you may now investigate all the other possibilities...
别管吉迪恩了
and forget about Gideon.
但，呃，那不是我们要求的
But, uh, that is not what we requested.
你要求进行最彻底的搜索，有记录的
You requested a most thorough search. It is in the record.
我们已尽一切可能为您提供方便
And we have used every means at our disposal to accommodate you.
你对这个问题的记录…
Your record on the subject...
不准确，阁下
is not precise, Your Excellency.
[听不见的对话]
[No Audible Dialogue]
当然，史波克先生，呃，我希望你不打算
Surely, Mr. Spock, uh, you do not intend, I hope,
在联邦和吉迪恩之间制造争端
to create a dispute between the Federation and Gideon?
阁下，争端是我们最不想发生的事
Your Excellency, a dispute is the farthest thing from our minds,
而且无需检查您的记录
and there's no need to check your records.
我只是想说我们声明的措辞
I merely suggest that the language of our statement...
可能没有完全按照预期 被理解
may not have been understood... exactly as intended.
史波克先生，你是一艘宇宙飞船的军官
Mr. Spock, you're an officer of a spaceship.
在你的职业生涯中，你使用许多工具
In your profession, you use many instruments,
武器来实现你的目标
tools and weapons to achieve your objectives.
是的，阁下
True, Your Excellency.
然而，外交唯一的工具就是语言
However, the only tool diplomacy has is language.
最重要的是要清楚地表达意思
It is of the utmost importance that the meaning be crystal clear.
阁下，我主要是一名科学家
Your Excellency, I am basically a scientist.
在我的职业中，清晰的表述也是必不可少的
Clarity of formulation is essential in my profession also.
我很高兴听到你这么说，也许你可以更努力地
I'm glad to hear it. Perhaps you could then make greater effort...
选择更准确的词
to choose your words more precisely.
你就让他这么糊弄过去？
Are you gonna let him get away with that?
史波克先生，不管你说什么，他都会曲解你的意思
No matter what you say, Mr. Spock, he'll twist your meaning.
是的，他很气人，长官，你怎么能忍的？
Yes, he's infuriating, sir. How can you stand it?
确定一切都已经完成前我们不能离开
We cannot leave without being sure that everything has been done.
现在你当然理解我们对此的感受
Now certainly you understand our feelings about that.
- 史波克先生！史波克先生！  - 是的，阁下
- Mr. Spock! Mr. Spock! - Yes, Your Excellency.
- 你还在吗？  - 是的，阁下
- Are you still there? - Yes, Your Excellency.
你的传输受受到很大干扰
There was considerable interference with your transmission.
噪音淹没了所说的话，
A lot of noise drowned out what was said.
- 请你重复一遍好吗？  - 很抱歉有噪音，阁下
- Would you repeat, please? - I apologize for the noise.
总之，我请求允许传送到吉迪恩
To summarize, I request permission to transport down to Gideon.
原谅我，史波克先生，无意批评你们的设备
Forgive me, Mr. Spock. No criticism of your equipment was intended.
但它让你的舰长踏上了一段奇怪的旅程
But it has sent your captain on some strange journey,
但愿是安全的
a safe one we all hope.
但这可能导致我们与你们联邦之间严重的冲突
But it could create for us serious incidents with your Federation,
现在你打算和另一位军官重蹈覆辙？
and now you propose to repeat this disaster with another officer.
- 真是疯狂  - 我不接受，史波克先生
- This would be madness. - I'll not take that, Mr. Spock!
传送装置状况良好，我亲自保证
That transporter was in perfect condition. I guarantee that myself!
传送我下去，我会向那些人证明…
Transport me down right this minute, and I'll prove to those...
- 先生们  - 斯科特先生
- gentlemen. - Mr. Scott,
你去传送室等待我的命令
you'll go to the transporter room and await my orders.
是的，史波克先生[抱怨]
Aye, Mr. Spock. [Grumbling]
[霍丁] 我无法理解，史波克先生
[Hodin] I could not quite make that out, Mr. Spock.
你能重复你说的话吗？
Would you be so good as to repeat what you said?
是的，阁下，飞船的轮机长正在解释
Yes, Your Excellency. The ship's engineer was explaining...
故障，确实存在，现在已修复
that the malfunction, which did exist, has now been repaired.
我们希望有机会测试设备
We would appreciate an opportunity to test the equipment.
请允许我传送到你们的议会厅
I, therefore, request permission to beam down to your council chamber.
但是，史波克先生，你…
But, Mr. Spock, you
阁下，请准许这一请求
Your Excellency, grant this one request.
你是一个非常执着的人，史波克先生
You are a very persistent fellow, Mr. Spock.
那好吧，呃…
Very well, then, uh
你能测试你那非常易怒的修理工的技术
You shall test the skill of your very excitable repairman.
有一个附带条件，我们不能冒进一步冲突的风险
There is one proviso. We cannot risk further incidents.
因此，你将把我的一名员工传送到你的船上
You will, therefore, transport a member of my staff to your ship.
让我们先看看这是否行得通
Let us first see if that works.
谢谢，阁下，接受你的提议
Thank you, Your Excellency. Your proposal is accepted.
- 斯科特先生  - 我是斯科特
- Mr. Scott. - Scott here.
准备传送吉迪恩议会代表上船
Prepare to beam aboard a representative of the Gideon council.
是的，长官
Aye, aye, sir.
我的助手会为你提供正确的…
My assistant will provide you with the proper
- 怎么说的？- 坐标，
- What is the word? - [Spock] Coordinates.
谢谢，继续，克罗达克
Thank you. Proceed, Krodak.
- 875  - [斯科特] 875
- 875. - [Scott] 875.
- 020
- 020.
- [斯科特] 020  - [克罗达克] 709
- [Scott] 020. - [Krodak] 709.
709.
传送
Energizing.
史波克先生，来自吉迪恩的先生到了
Mr. Spock, the gentleman from Gideon is here.
阁下，您的助理已安全抵达
Your Excellency, your assistant has arrived safely,
我现在准备传送到吉迪恩
and I am now ready to transport down to Gideon.
别那么快，史波克先生
Now, now, not so fast, Mr. Spock.
那完全是另一回事，我们一致同意允许
That is quite a different matter. We agreed to allow...
一名代表踏上我们的土地，你的舰长
one representative on our soilyour captain.
先生，我们的舰长仍然下落不明
Sir, our captain is still missing,
我现在要求允许我按照我们的约定传送到吉迪恩
and I now demand that I be allowed to transport to Gideon as we agreed.
请原谅我，史波克先生
Forgive me, Mr. Spock,
但我在达成该协议时越权了
but I overstepped my authority when I made that agreement.
然而，你的请求将会得到处理
However, your request will be taken up...
在吉迪恩议会的下一次全体会议上
at the next full session of Gideon's council.
斯科特先生，把来自吉迪恩的先生传送下去
Mr. Scott, beam down the gentleman from Gideon.
是的，史波克先生，我正将他直接发送到相同的坐标
Yes, Mr. Spock. I'm sending him straight to the same coordinates.
就在我开始认为你可能会找到
Just when I was beginning to think you might find...
一份外交官的新职业的时候，史波克先生
a whole new career as a diplomat, Mr. Spock.
不要放弃希望，医生，乌乎拉上尉，联系星际舰队指挥部
Do not give up hope, Doctor. Lieutenant Uhura, contact Starfleet Command.
要求立即回复我们
Demand an immediate reply to our request...
传送至吉迪恩的请求
for permission to beam down to Gideon.
是的，史波克先生
Yes, Mr. Spock.
企业号呼叫星际舰队指挥部
Enterprise to Starfleet Command.
我是柯克舰长，红色优先级，红色优先级
Captain Kirk here. Red priority. Red priority.
- 它不在工作状态？  - 好像是
- Isn't it in working order? - It seems to be.
那么应该有人听到了你
Then someone should have heard you.
我是柯克舰长，请回答红色优先级
Captain Kirk here. Please answer red priority.
请回答红色优先级
Please answer red priority.
如果有人在听，但他们不回答
Well, if someone is listening, they're not answering.
他们为什么要这样做？
Why should they do that?
他们不会
They wouldn't.
- 你做了什么？  - 带我们脱离了曲速
- What did you do? - Took the ship out of warp speed.
- 脱离什么？  - 空间术语
- Out of what? - Space terminology.
我们不再以超光速移动
We're no longer moving faster than the speed of light.
我减到了亚光速，直到查明我们的位置
I've trimmed down to sub-light speed until we find out where we are.
- 感觉一样  - 当然一样
- It feels the same. - Of course it does.
也许就是一样的
Maybe it is the same.
那么，船慢下来了吗？
Well, has the ship slowed down?
如果你相信，是的
If you can believe that, we have.
拜托，别告诉我现在天空出故障了
Oh, please! Don't tell me the sky is out of order now.
真安静
So quiet.
真平静
So peaceful.
实际并不，你知道的
It isn't really, you know.
它很漂亮
And it's beautiful!
是的，它是
Yes. Yes, it is.
非常，非常漂亮
Very, very beautiful.
只有我们
And we're alone.
你能让它持续很长时间吗？
Can you make it last a long, long time?
你希望它持续多久？
How long would you like it to last?
- 永远  - 让我们看看
- Forever. - Well, let's see.
能量，那不是问题，它能再生，还有食物
Power, that's no problem: it regenerates. And food. We
我们有足够的食物养活430名船员五年
We have enough to feed a crew of 430 for five years.
- 所以这应该够我们用…  - 永远
- So that should last us... - Forever.
我一生都梦想着独处
All my life I've dreamed of being alone.
大多数人都害怕孤独
Most people are afraid of being alone.
我的故乡，人们梦寐以求
Where I come from, people dream of it.
为什么？为什么吉迪恩的人会这样？
Why? Why are the people of Gideon like that?
吉迪恩？
Gideon?
我告诉过你我不知道我来自哪里，我的星球是什么
I told you, I don't know where I come from, what my planet is.
- 可能是吉迪恩  - 有那么重要吗？
- It might be Gideon. - Does it matter so much?
是的，它也许能帮我确定我们的位置
Yes. It might help me pinpoint our location.
你也许能找到你的船员
And then you might find your crew.
和你在一起，我忘了一定还有其他人
Being here with you, I forgot there must be others.
我羡慕你的忠诚
I envy you your sense of loyalty.
我想减轻你的恐惧感
I want to ease your feeling of dread,
你担心你所有的船员都不复存在了
your fear that all your crew no longer exists.
我必须联系操控我们的人
I've got to contact whoever is manipulating us.
一定有办法
There must be a way!
奥多纳，你能…
Odona, can you...
记得为什么你们的人会梦想独处吗？
remember why your people dream of being alone?
- 因为他们永远不可能  - 为什么？
- Because they never can be. - Why?
是什么让独处如此不可能？
What makes it so impossible to be alone?
因为我们人太多了，太多了
Because there are so many of us. So many.
没有位置，
There is no place,
没有街道，没有房子，
no street, no house,
没有花园，没有海滩
no garden, no beach,
没有没有人的山
no mountain that is not filled with people.
我们每个人都会杀人
Each one of us would kill...
为了找到一个属于自己的地方而
in order to find a place alone to himself.
他们愿意为此而死
Yet would willingly die for it,
如果可以的话
if they could.
谁派你来的？
Who sent you here?
没有人命令奥多纳
No one commands Odona!
我不是被派到这里的
I was not sent here.
你是来杀人的？
You have come to kill?
奥多纳，你是来死的吗？
Odona, have you come to die?
我不知道，我不在乎
I don't know. I don't care!
我只知道我在这里
I only know I'm here.
我只知道我很开心
I only know I'm happy.
现在我所要做的就是找到一个医疗箱，
Now, all I have to do is find a medical kit,
我可以完全治愈它
and I can completely cure this.
- 治愈？  - 是的，发炎会消失
- Cure? - Yes, the irritation would be gone.
如果你没有找到会发生什么？
What will happen if you do not find one?
你会生病并死去吗？
Will you become sick and die?
哦，不，这么小的伤不会
Oh, no. Over something as simple as this?
不，它最终会自行痊愈，但是…
No, It'll cure itself eventually, but
你知道吗，
Do you know, uh
我甚至不记得这是怎么发生的
I don't even remember how this happened.
[连续轻击声]
[Soft Thrumming]
你听到了吗？
Do you hear that?
是的，听起来像一个引擎
Yes. It sounds like an engine.
不
No.
这艘飞船的引擎不会发出那种声音
The ship's engines don't make that kind of sound.
但是设备有问题，会是这样吗？
But there is something wrong with the equipment. Could that be it?
我知道这艘船可能发出的每一种声音
I know every sound that this ship might make.
那是外面传来的
That's coming from outside.
- 一场风暴…  - 有可能是风暴
- A storm might... - A storm might
但是你听不到它
But you wouldn't be able to hear it.
来吧
Come on.
这是一个观景台，我们能看到外面
This is a viewing port. We'll be able to see outside.
如果有风暴，我们将能够看到它
If there's a storm, we'll be able to see it.
如果行得通
If it works.
人，人的面孔
People. The faces of people!
然后是星星
And then the stars.
发生了什么？外面有什么？
What's happening? What's out there?
[轻击声停止]
[Thrumming Stops]
声音没了
The sound is gone.
像那些人的心跳
It was like the heartbeat of all those people,
还有成千上万的人，压在船上
and thousands upon thousands more, pressing against the ship.
但你说我们正在穿越太空
But you said we were moving through space.
是的，我说过
Yes, I said that.
那么人们不可能在外面
Then the people can't be out there.
是的他们可以
Yes, they can.
请不要吓唬我
Please don't frighten me.
这可能是海市蜃楼，它们可能存在于我们的脑海中
It could be a mirage. They could exist in our minds.
你的意思是我们要疯了
You mean that we're going mad.
或者某种力量正在我们的脑海中
Or some power is creating the illusion in our minds...
制造我们离你们星球很近的错觉
that we are somewhere near your planet.
但为什么？
But why?
我不知道
I don't know.
I don't know!
我想我知道是怎么回事了
I think I have an idea
这样我们就不会一直试图找出我们在哪里
so that we won't keep trying to find out where we are:
我们会满足于留在这里
that we'll be content to stay here!
哦，知足！
Oh, be content!
知足？
Be content?
知足！
Be content!
除非我发现我的船员发生了什么事
Not until I find out what happened to my crew.
- 他们死了吗？  - 我不知道
- Are they dead? - I don't know.
你杀了他们，这样你就可以将船占为己有了吗？
Did you kill them so you could have the ship to yourself?
舰长…
Captain.
舰长
Captain,
我不对劲
something's happening to me.
我以前从未有过这种感觉，
I never felt like this before.
我以前也从未有过这种感觉
I've never felt like this before either.
这是人们
Is this the way one looks...
生病时的样子吗？
when one is developing a sickness?
你的星球上没有疾病，记得吗？
There's no sickness on your planet, remember?
现在会有了，会有疾病
Now there will be. There will be sickness.
会有死亡
There will be death.
[开门]
[Door Opening]
- 霍丁  - 是的，柯克舰长
- Hodin! - Yes, Captain Kirk.
我们的实验已经通过了第一阶段
Our experiment has passed the first stage.
让我进去，我可以帮她
Let me in there. I can help her.
- 我们不需要你的药  - 但她病了
- We have no need of your medicines. - But she's ill!
我们为她的病感谢你
And we're grateful to you for her illness.
你做得很好，我的女儿
You have done well, my daughter.
好好保护舰长，
Guard the captain well.
我们将需要他很长时间
We shall need him for a long time.
我深表同情，但星际舰队
I sympathize deeply, but Starfleet...
不能无视联邦指令
cannot override Federation directives in this matter.
上将，船员们不会明白的
Admiral, the crew will not understand it.
你的船员有兴趣挑起战争吗？
Has your crew suddenly become interested in provoking a war?
这不是星际舰队的使命
That is not Starfleet's mission.
我们只想救舰长的命
We wish only to save the life of the captain.
你没有就此事向联邦
You have not proved your case to the Federation,
或星际舰队证明你的情况
or to Starfleet, for that matter.
我确信我可以做到让您满意，上将
I am positive that I can do so to your satisfaction, Admiral.
从我第一次与大使交流，就一直确信
I have been convinced, since my first exchange with the ambassador,
船长被俘虏了
that the captain has been taken prisoner.
已证明是事实，史波克先生，
Granted as fact, Mr. Spock.
我现在知道他被关押在哪里了
I now know where the captain is being held,
如果他被关押在我们传送他去的同一个地方
if he is being held at the same place to which we transported him.
他们不会在议会厅伤害他
They would not dare harm him in the Gideon council chamber.
长官，他没有被关押在议会厅，
Sir, the captain is not being held in the Gideon council chamber.
- 他被关在附近  - 你回答了是什么和在哪里，
- He is being held nearby. - You have answered what and where.
我在等你解释为什么
I'm waiting for your explanation of why.
因为，星球被我们的传感器屏蔽了
Since the planet is shielded from our sensors,
如果不进行调查，我们就无法确定这一点
we cannot establish that without on-the-spot investigation.
你有证据表明舰长的生命受到威胁吗？
Do you have evidence the captain's life is threatened?
- 拒绝  - 上将
- Permission denied. - Admiral,
我谨正式指出，你的决定是武断的
I wish to state for the record that your decision is arbitrary.
以上
So noted.
会持续很长时间吗？
Will it last long?
这取决于感染者的实力
That depends on the strength of the one infected.
你有很大的力量
You have great strength.
你怎么知道我什么时候死？
How will you know when I am to die?
你的体温会很高
Your body temperature will be very great.
你会看到我们，但你不会知道我们是谁
You will see us, but you will not know who we are.
- 我必须在那之前见到他，父亲  - 休息，现在躺着别动
- I must see him before then, Father. - Rest. Now lie still.
你感到巨大的痛苦吗？
Do you feel great pain?
是的
Yes,
我的手臂和大腿
in my arms and thighs.
感到疼痛是什么感觉？
What is it like to feel pain?
它就像是…
It is like...
…就像当你看到人们对幸福没有希望时，父亲
like when you see the people have no hope for happiness, Father.
你感到非常绝望
You feel great despair,
你的心情很沉重，
and your heart is heavy,
因为你知道你无能为力
because you know you can do nothing.
痛苦就是这样
Pain is like that.
你的勇气使我感到无比自豪
Your courage gives me great pride.
- 让我看看她  - 还不行
- Let me see her. - Not yet.
你不知道她可能有什么病
You don't know what she may have.
但我们知道，她患有纯素脉络丛脑膜炎
But we do. She has Vegan-choriomeningitis.
这是罕见且致命的，如果不在24小时内治疗，
That's very rare, and always fatal if not treated within 24 hours.
我知道，它几乎要了我的命
I know. It almost killed me.
是的，我们的总理在我们的谈判中了解到
Yes. Our prime minister learned about you during our negotiations.
这就是我们带你来这里的原因
That's why we brought you here.
你的血液提供了感染她的微生物
Your blood provided the micro organisms which infected her.
我的手臂就是这样受伤的
That's how my arm got hurt.
是的，正如奥多纳告诉你的，我们这里不需要医生
Yes, as Odona told you, we have no need for medical practitioners here.
很抱歉，伤害了你使我们感到非常不安
Our apologies. We were unforgivably awkward to have hurt you.
你疯了
You're mad.
不，我们很绝望
No. We are desperate.
我不明白
I don't understand...
星际舰队怎么能不允许我们传送下去寻找舰长
how Starfleet can deny permission to beam down to search for the captain.
他们不求我们理解，医生
They did not ask for our understanding, Doctor.
他们怎么能要求我们
I don't see how they expect us to sit here...
坐等着船长再次出现呢？
and wait for the captain to reappear.
不幸的是，我必须违反星际舰队的直接命令
Unfortunately, I must violate a direct order from Starfleet.
这是最好的决定，史波克，我和你一起
That's the best possible decision you could make, Spock. I'm with you.
我不会掉以轻心，医生
I do not make it lightly, Doctor.
然而，指挥部知道霍丁大使
However, Command knows that Ambassador Hodin...
一直没有对我们说实话
has not been totally honest with us.
乌乎拉上尉，重复原始吉迪恩坐标用以传送
Lieutenant Uhura, repeat original Gideon coordinates for beam down.
875，020，079
875, 020, 079.
斯科特先生，给你的坐标呢？
Mr. Scott, coordinates given you?
875，020，709
875, 020, 709.
坐标不匹配
Coordinates don't match.
正是，我会立刻传送下去，斯科特先生，你来掌舵
Precisely. I shall beam down at once. Mr. Scott, you have the con.
我去哪我的医疗三录仪，在传送室和你见面
I'll pick up my medical tricorder, meet you in the transporter room.
不行，医生，我不能承担
Negative, Doctor. I cannot accept the responsibility...
命令官员违反指令的责任
for ordering a fellow officer to violate a Starfleet directive.
我只能为自己做决定
I can make such a decision only for myself.
我不是要你替我做决定
I'm not asking you to make the decision for me.
形势迫使我这样做，医生
The situation forces me to do so, Doctor.
在这种情况下，这是你能做出的最糟糕的决定
In that case, it's the worst possible decision you can make.
这不会花很长时间
This will not take long.
这不就是柯克舰长离开前说的话吗？
Isn't that just about what Captain Kirk said before he left?
柯克舰长
Captain Kirk.
我是史波克，柯克舰长？
Spock here. Captain Kirk!
[仪器嗡嗡声]
[ Instrument Humming ]
你给联邦的报告是一堆谎言
Your report to the Federation was a tissue of lies.
你把吉迪恩的环境，物理，文化条件
You described environmental, physical, cultural conditions...
- 描述得像天堂一样  - 本来确实如此，
- that would make Gideon a paradise. - And so it was!
很久以前，我们所描述的都是真实的
A long, long time ago what we described was true!
吉迪恩的大气一直是无菌的
The atmosphere on Gideon has always been germfree.
人们在身体和精神上的完美中茁壮成长
And the people flourished in their physical and spiritual perfection.
最终，甚至寿命也增加了
Eventually, even the life span increased.
死亡对我们来说几乎是陌生的
Death became almost unknown to us.
只有当身体不再能够自我再生时才会发生
It occurred only when the body could no longer regenerate itself.
现在这种情况只发生在非常老的人身上
And that happens now only to the very old.
这是大多数人都会羡慕的条件
Those are conditions most people would envy.
但吉迪恩人并不觉得它令人羡慕
But Gideon did not find it enviable.
出生率持续上升，人口增长
The birth rate continued to rise, and the population grew,
直到现在，吉迪恩被包裹在一团生命物质中…
until now Gideon is encased in a living mass...
我们不能休息，没有平安，没有喜乐
who can find no rest, no peace, no joy.
你为什么不引进
Then why haven't you introduced...
男性和女性绝育的新技术？
any of the new techniques to sterilize men and women?
每个器官都会自我更新，这是不可能的
Every organ renews itself. It would be impossible.
那让你的人民了解避孕工具
Then let your people learn about the devices to prevent conception.
联邦将提供你们所需要的一切
The Federation will provide anything you need.
但你明白，吉迪恩人一直相信
But you see, the people of Gideon have always believed...
生命是神圣的
that life is sacred,
对生命的热爱
that the love of life...
是最好的礼物
is the greatest gift.
这是吉迪恩人不可动摇的真理
That is the one unshakable truth of Gideon.
这种压倒性的对生命的热爱
And this overwhelming love of life...
导致了我们的再生能力
has developed our regenerative capacity...
和我们的长寿
and our great longevity.
还有你现在面临的巨大苦难
And the great misery which you now face.
令人痛苦的事实，舰长
That is bitterly true, Captain.
然而，我们不能否认塑造我们进化的真相
Nevertheless, we cannot deny the truth which shaped our evolution.
我们无权干涉
We are incapable of destroying or interfering with...
我们深爱的事物的创造
the creation of that which we love so deeply life...
从胎儿到发育的生命，各种形式的生命
in every form, from fetus to developed being.
它违背了我们的传统，违背了我们的本性
It is against our tradition, against our very nature.
我们根本做不到
We simply could not do it.
然而你可以杀死一个年轻的女孩
Yet you can kill a young girl!
我们正试图重新调整整个文明的生命周期
We're trying to readjust the life cycle of an entire civilization.
你在杀死你自己的女儿！
You're killing your own daughter!
我女儿希望让你感受到吉迪恩人的痛苦
My daughter hoped to make you feel the agony of Gideon.
但这是不可能的
But it was impossible.
没有陌生人可以意识到
No stranger could realize...
在这里生命有多恐怖
the horror that life can be here.
我不会乞求你理解我的悲伤
I will not beg for your understanding of my personal grief,
也不会为了获得你的合作​​而夸大它
nor will I parade it for you to gain your cooperation.
我对女儿的爱
My love for my daughter...
太深了，无法表达
is too deep for display.
我对她的骄傲甚至更深
My pride in her runs even deeper.
我女儿自由地选择做她正在做的事情
My daughter freely chose to do what she is doing,
正如吉迪恩人可以自由选择
as the people of Gideon are free to choose.
你需要的病毒非常罕见，
The virus you need is very rare.
谁来提供？
Who will provide it?
你会留下来，你的血液会提供它
You will stay. Your blood will provide it.
不，先生，不是我，
Oh, no, sir, not me.
你有很多方法可用 我只提到了几个，
You have many methods available. I've mentioned only a few.
我不会为此目的献出我的生命，我有很多计划，
I do not offer my life for this purpose. I have many plans.
我对奥多纳抱有希望，不是死亡
And I have hopes other than death for Odona.
我女儿恳求你留下来
My daughter pleaded with you to stay.
我们之间所说的
What was said...
和发生的一切都别让人知道
and what happened between us was for us alone.
她希望你会爱她并想要留下来
She hoped you would love her and wish to stay.
所以这就是你的计划
So that was your plan
我会被她的魔咒所迷惑
that I would fall so under her spell...
我会放弃我的自由，
that I would give up my freedom...
成为一个自愿的牺牲品
and become a willing sacrifice.
和我们在一起，我们很绝望
Stay with us. We're desperate.
[哔哔]
[Communicator Beeps]
奥多纳的体温在上升，
Odona's fever is rising.
她在呼唤詹姆斯·柯克的名字
She's calling the name of James Kirk.
你看，你现在不能离开我们
You see, you cannot leave us now.
去找她
Go to her.
企业号的
Exact duplicate...
精确复制品
of the Enterprise.
但完全无法运行
But completely inoperative.
史波克呼叫企业号，史波克呼叫企业号
Spock to Enterprise. Spock to Enterprise.
我是斯科特，史波克先生
Scott here, Mr. Spock.
我在企业号的舰桥上和你通话
I am speaking to you from the bridge of the Enterprise.
你在哪儿？
You're where?
在企业号的舰桥上，斯科特先生
On the bridge of the Enterprise, Mr. Scott.
那些是你强调的坐标
Those were the coordinates you insisted on.
它们是对的，
And they were correct.
我在企业号的精确复制品上
I am on board an exact duplicate of the Enterprise.
企业号的精确复制品？
An exact duplicate of the Enterprise?
它在轨道上吗，史波克先生？
Is it in orbit, Mr. Spock?
在轨道上，医生？
In orbit, Doctor?
从某种意义上说，
In a manner of speaking.
吉迪恩在轨道上，而飞船在吉迪恩上
Gideon is in orbit, and the ship is on Gideon.
一个好的开始，舰长呢？
Well, that's a beginning, but what about the captain?
我确定他在某个地方，
I'm sure he's on board somewhere.
我在收集生命读数，通话完毕
I'm picking up life readings. Spock out.
[史波克] ：舰船日志，星历5423.8，
[ Spock's Voice ] Ship's Log: Star date 5423.8.
史波克大副报告
First Officer Spock reporting.
很明显，吉迪恩人将柯克舰长传送到了
Obviously the Gideon's have transported Captain Kirk...
企业号的复制品上，迷惑他的头脑，
onto this replica of the Enterprise to so confuse his mind...
使他容易受到一些实验的影响
as to make him susceptible to some extraordinary experiment.
我的目的是找到舰长
It is my intention to locate the captain and warn him...
并在实验结束前警告他，逻辑表明
before the experiment reaches its conclusion, which logic indicates...
一旦舰长知道，就意味着他生命的终结
means the end of the captain's life as he knows it.
[呻吟]
[ Moaning ]
请允许我把麦考伊医生带下来，
If you don't allow me to bring Dr. McCoy down here,
否则来不及给她做任何治疗了
it'll soon be too late to do anything for her.
我们已经告诉过你，她和我的愿望是
We have told you, it is her wish and mine...
不要干扰病毒的自然过程
that there be no interference with the natural progress of the virus.
她的死是不必要的
Her death is unnecessary.
如果她活着，她的血液将提供
Even if she lives, her blood will provide...
你需要的与我相同的血清
the same serum you need as mine would.
不，她的英年早逝
No. Her death at so young an age...
能让人们相信我们的生命周期是可以改变的
will let the people know for certain that our life cycle can be changed.
这个象征将培养出敬业的年轻志愿者
It's the symbol that'll bring forth the dedicated young volunteers.
他们新血液中的血清会改变吉迪恩
The serum in their new blood will change Gideon,
它将再次成为曾经的天堂
and it will, once more, be the paradise it was.
[呻吟]
[Moaning]
我很高兴你在这里
I'm glad that you are here.
我的时间还多吗？
Is the time short?
不多了
Very short.
我请求你让我们的旅程永远持续下去
And I asked you to make our journey last forever.
它在这里开始
Oh. It began here.
它可以继续
And it can continue.
只要你允许，
If only you'll allow me,
我就能治愈你
I can cure you.
我不害怕会发生的事
I'm not afraid of what will happen.
只是现在…
It is just that now...
我全心全意地想永远和你在一起
I wish with all my heart to stay with you forever.
阁下，
Your Excellency.
舰长，你看起来不错，星际舰队的分析是正确的
Captain, you're looking well. Starfleet's analysis was correct.
史波克先生，我们有个病人给麦考伊医生，让斯科提传送我们上去
Mr. Spock, we have a patient for Dr. McCoy. Have Scotty beam us up.
史波克呼叫企业号，史波克呼叫企业号
Spock to Enterprise. Spock to Enterprise.
- 我是斯科特  - 三个人要传送，斯科特先生
- Scott here. - Three to beam up, Mr. Scott.
- 相同的坐标？- 不是，
- Same coordinates? - Negative.
锁定我的通讯器信号
Lock in on my communicator signal.
阁下，请不要干涉
Your Excellency, please do not interfere.
我已经有了一个需要与高层解决的严重问题
I already have one serious problem to resolve with upper echelons.
嗯，真险，但你挺过来了
Well, it was close, but you made it.
我痊愈了？
I am cured?
对，就像舰长一样
Right, just like the captain.
你应该愤怒地大喊，而不是微笑
Instead of smiling at me, you should be shouting in anger.
为什么，因为你又好了？
Why? Because you're well again?
不，因为我假装…
No. Because I pretended to be
你怎么还能忍受看我，在我那样骗你之后？
How can you bear to look at me after the way I deceived you?
至少你欠我让我看你的特权
At least you owe me the privilege of letting me look at you.
你真是个绅士，柯克舰长
You are a gentleman, Captain Kirk.
谢谢你，女士
Thank you, ma'am.
吉迪恩不再需要你了，
You are no longer needed on Gideon.
我可以代替你在那里
I can take your place there.
这是你想做的吗？
Is that what you wanted?
那是我必须做的
That is what I must do.
现在那里需要我
I am needed there now.
到处都需要你，奥多纳
You're needed everywhere, Odona.
它不像我们的船
It is not like our ship.
哦，不，完全一样，只是这艘能飞
Oh, yes, it is. It's exactly the same. Only this one works.
它去过许多其他星球？
It goes to many other planets?
是的，整个银河系，还有一个区别，
Yes, it goes to the whole galaxy, with another difference
这艘有很多人
this one is crowded.
对你来说似乎很拥挤？
It seems crowded to you?
现在确实如此
It does now.
你要留在船上吗？
Are you going to stay on the ship?
是的，奥多纳，我必须这样做
Yes, Odona, I have to.
尽管我的星球如此拥挤，
As crowded as my planet is,
但我希望它能再容纳一个人
I could wish for it to hold one more person.
柯克呼叫传送控制，传送一个人到吉迪恩星球
Kirk to transporter control. One to beam down to the planet Gideon.
我会想念你的，詹姆斯·柯克舰长
I will miss you, Captain James Kirk.